A2 KSL API.
And then KSL API just acts kind of as a
wrapper or a proxy around the new back
end image service. I don't have.
memorized all the renditions that CARS
asks for.
I know it's going to ask for some.
And there may be a very small amount of
business logic that happens in KSL API,
but I don't think there's much anymore.
I think it's primarily just a wrapper.
I'm pretty sure it's the same with Cappy
as well.
We go directly to CAPI,
and then all the business logic,
it's just the wrapper for the news.
The new one.
Okay.
Right, so if the back end could...
provide a signed URL.
then I don't think it would take much,
if any, work on KSL API for cars.
I think it would more just be telling the
front end to use that method rather than
posting to KSL API.
I think the front end work would be
pretty minimal.
But we would like to do that because we
are breaking our ADR of not touching the
Yeah.
APIs directly because of these image
uploads.
We are touching KSL API and KAPI directly
both for image uploading because we don't
have site URLs.
Yeah.
Okay, so...
If I understand the problem correctly,
is we want on cars and classifieds to use
the signed URL option.
And so you reach out,
you get assigned to URL,
and then the front end is going to upload
directly to that bucket.
I don't know how much you guys were
thinking through that problem when you
guys were working on the PAL.
Is there any particularities on how that
upload process should work from you guys'
perspective?
Do we upload directly to the bucket or do
we send the signed URL through GraphQL,
which is supposed to upload that to the
bucket?
No,
so there is an actual ADR to where when
it comes to like signed URL stuff,
getting the signed URL can go through the
GraphQL,
but uploading directly to the bucket is
how those work.
Was that how we do it on like videos and
profiles and stuff? Okay, cool. Yeah.
The profile strength, yeah.
Yeah, videos, videos work that way.
Profile images work that way.
Yeah, so my thoughts are is, yeah,
so we get that signed URL,
we get that bucket,
we upload directly to it.
Ben the, I think on the profile side,
don't we get like a...
A PubSub message from itself saying.
There's a, yeah, pubs up events happen.
So yeah,
as soon as the file is finished uploading,
the bucket sends out a pub-sub event that
we can listen for. And then we pick it up,
grab the image and process the image,
and let the front end.
And then we do right now just pull from
the front end.
asking, is this done? Is this done?
Is it done?
But we can do GraphQL subscriptions and
do a, like a web socket or I guess,
I'm not sure what it's called,
where the front end gets notified when
it's done. And so instead of polling,
it gets immediate notification.
Be nice.
Okay, so if the...
Image service could set up a socket,
or you said GraphQL would set up a socket?
Yeah,
because the front end communicates with
GraphQL,
so I'm not sure exactly how to do it.
In.
We talked about doing it again for the
jobs apply stuff that we just did,
but we decided it was too complicated to
try to fit it in our, you know,
trying to do this jobs apply thing in.
extremely short timeline. So yeah,
I think it would be great, but...
We haven't figured out the particulars of
how to make it work.
Okay.
Okay,
so another question I have when it comes
to images,
currently they get uploaded and then...
When does the front end then know what to
render on the PAL and what do they show
the user? I'm not familiar with that part.
Hopefully my question makes sense.
And.
I think it grabs it from the listing.
They can render that.
Well, yeah, right as the user uploads it,
JavaScript reads the file and displays A
Now.
thumbnail.
And then it goes and does its uploading.
Yeah.
And that's what's going to be there until,
like, there's a page refresh or someone.
Leaves and comes back,
and then we'll just read the images off
of the listing itself.
Okay, so when this will upload,
it'll upload the photos.
The back end will then apply the photos
in the proper order in which they were
sent.
So we need like an index of this is photo
#2 or whatever, right? And then we...
No.
Yeah.
Got it.
Now we might need to pass in an order
number.
I'm not sure if we're just because they
might upload at different speeds.
You know,
the first photo might be bigger than the
Yeah.
other photos,
and so the other photos get there first
before the first photo.
So we probably need to specify the order.
Somewhere.
Yeah, as part of the metadata on the URL.
As, yeah, yeah,
we could do that in the metadata.
Yeah.
Okay, and then...
So those will load.
And then,
so once the front end finishes those
uploads, does it just display the, like,
great, cool, this is uploaded, shows it,
and then at that point,
you can like drag and reorder the photos,
and then it just submits a backend
request of photo reorder, right?
And that photo order,
I want to say goes through GraphQL now.
I also want to say that.
It didn't used to.
Yeah, it should go through GraphQL.
I think pretty much everything from
Marketplace front end goes through
Um...
GraphQL, except image uploads.
The image upload? Yeah.
Um,
and then does does the photo reordering?
Is that like blocked from the user being
able to do something until the photos are
finished uploading and the front end can
verify that all the photos are actually
successfully on the listing document in
the database in the back end?
Or is there like some potential race
conditions that everybody need to be
Um...
concerned with?
I'm pretty sure the forum version of the
postal listing page doesn't look at that
because it's at the top and we figure
they'll be on the forum for a minute.
That may be kind of an oversight,
but the stepper does.
look and it will prevent moving on to the
next step until uploads are finished.
It's not doing a verification on the back
end.
It's just it knows something's in flight.
And as soon as it's not in flight anymore,
then it lets the user move on.
Okay, so I guess as soon as,
so the in-flight is, it's still uploading.
Yes.
And then once it's done uploading.
Aren't they?
Yeah, aren't they separate components too,
like the uploader and just the image
thumbnails that you can?
Reorganize.
Yeah.
So you can't even,
probably can't even drag and drop the,
or drag around the uploader,
the photos as they're uploading because
it's not even the right component that
has that ability, right?
Yeah,
they have to finish uploading before
they're draggable.
Yeah.
Okay, then.
I think that's the case as well in the
form version.
I don't think we can get race conditions
there.
I think we probably accounted for that.
Well,
there could be a race condition if it
finishes uploading,
but then once the bucket sends the
pub-sub message,
then delivers it to the service,
Oh, in that.
the service that was just attaching it to
the listing itself,
there's probably some time frame in which
a user could drag and reorder a photo
Yeah.
before it's actually attached to the
listing.
In a new service, yeah, that could happen.
Usually,
usually the front end doesn't know,
like with the video,
the video goes through all the checks and
everything before we tell the front end
that it's done.
Isn't that right?
Okay.
Yeah.
And so we could do this.
So it has to go through the whole entire
back end process before the front end is,
Yeah, before the front end says it's done.
so complete for the front end is we can
pull the back end and say,
is this photo done yet? Yes or no?
And done means it's been uploaded,
it's been scanned,
it's been processed and attached to the
Processed and.
listing,
and now it's like there's an actual
object on the listing itself.
Right.
K.
That would be my assumption.
Are we doing a lot of extra processing on
these photos like we are for videos?
Thumbnails and...
are not thumbnails,
but just all the crops,
all the different sizes.
All the filters, yeah.
Yeah, we one concern we we make.
Filters.
We assume that users are moving on while
the video is processing.
It can take 2 minutes, perhaps.
We don't assume that with photos now.
I don't know how common it is for users
to reorder them,
but if it's going to take a couple of
minutes,
that's going to be a pretty painful
exercise for people on the stepper in
particular,
because that's the only thing they can do
on the stepper.
We can let the user move on while it's
processing, just like we do for videos.
But as far as if they want to look and
review,
look at and review the order of their
photos,
they're going to have to come back if we
have to wait for a bunch of extra
processing.
Can we...
Ohh,
I'm wondering if some of the extra
And we have to, they have to be totally.
processing.
I'm wondering if some of that extra
processing can just happen asynchronously
in the background where it's like we
attached the main photo with like,
you know, the main copy of it,
the one that they directly uploaded to
the listing and say, it's done.
And so you can now go render,
reorder these and all these other types
of things.
But then some background asynchronous
processing goes and does all those extra
renditions,
and then I can just look for the...
proper index instead of assuming the
index and just attach it to the right
spot.
Another question. So with the stepper,
I'm assuming they can go back and forth,
That could be nice.
right? And be like, oh,
actually I need to go.
Can we like have like little,
some little image uploader modal going on
that's just saying, hey,
let them go forward,
but let them know that their images are
still uploading?
that's visible and it lets them know when
it's done and they can click it and go
back and reorder images. I don't know,
just wondering.
We could, we don't.
Right now they just live on the one step
and we just don't let them move on until
the upload's done.
But I don't see any reason we couldn't if
we get some product buy-off on that.
Another reason to potentially go back to
that image step for you guys with the
with the stepper PAL is if we do
implement a editor,
if that is interesting to your users at
all,
they might want to go back and post
process after they've been uploaded.
What does the Editor allow them to do?
Rotate and crop.
I mean...
Maybe, I don't know.
I don't know what,
if classified users are more likely to
want to do that than Car users,
I don't know.
I'm sure they would like the feature.
Apparently it was a big services thing.
Apparently they liked using that for
Ohh.
businesses like using it on their
services. I don't know why,
but that's why it exists basically.
Well, I think, yeah,
I think some of those problems might be
future tweets and stuff like that that we
want to do.
I'm thinking that the only thing we're
trying to solve is just the back end
portion of making it available to upload
the assigned URLs.
Abe, do you happen to know if our editor,
if that also has to go directly through
Cappy?
Not anymore.
Not anymore for their GraphQL.
I mean, because it, yeah,
the way the editor worked before,
we were sending all of the editor data so
that they could go back to the original
state if they decide to edit the image
again. We're not saving any of that.
We're just saving the new version of the
image.
And so,
that's all we would send through the
But does it, if it goes, if it re-uploads.
signed URL.
Then the Editor does still need to.
Oh, but okay,
but because we're not saving the data,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Because it's just a it's just a re-upload
at that point. OK, yeah.
Okay, so a crop and rotate is just,
it's considered a completely new image
Yeah, so that's a, yeah.
It's a destructive, yeah.
that's replacing one.
Okay.
Mhm.
The old,
the old classifieds editor did save that
What?
data.
That was part of CAPI where it would have
the coordinates and like the rotation
angle and stuff and it would actually
save that as part of the image object.
But we don't do that anymore, so.
No worries.
Yeah,
to just cut scope when we're adding in
the image editor,
we just kept it really simple. And so far,
Yeah.
nobody cares, so.
Yes.
Yeah, I mean,
I'm sure at that point it's like,
you have the original image,
just re-upload it and make a new crop.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
If you don't, that's your fault, not ours.
Okay,
let's see if there's any other questions
I have.
Um...
Yeah,
I suppose that's the only other thing
that I'm trying to think through is, okay,
we obviously want this code to be unified
code and not have anything living in CAPI
or KSL API anymore.
And so we're going to have to have the
listing service handling the attaching
these listing or these photos to their
listings. With that being said,
the listing service doesn't currently
handle.
Cars.
But my thoughts there is we just add
another deployment that is like specific
to cars right now that handles attaching
photos and doing some of its rendition
stuff into the existing structure that it
needs separate from the classifieds one
and we just have two different
deployments running that.
are handling this data processing,
one for classifieds, one for cars,
and then eventually once cars is in
classifieds,
it just adopts the classifieds thing.
And.
I think that's probably fine,
but so I'll just have to think through
that part one and how it works with the
listing service and to them with the fact
that it's going to be touching two
different Mongo databases,
which I don't love, but...
I think we kind of need to at this point.
Yeah,
until we're able to get all of our data
But I should.
in one place,
I think that's what you're going to have
to do.
So I think, yeah,
just the goal for our team then probably
is just making sure that the back end can
be completely,
or the front end can then upload to the
assigned URLs and the KSL and KAPI back
end pieces of image processing are just
completely eliminated, no longer needed.
No.
All right,
I don't think I have any other questions.
Anybody else have anything that I think
we might need to be aware of and think
through and talk about?
I think it would be great if this could
be built in a way to where we could.
I either.
What am I trying to say?
The profile image uploads,
those don't necessarily need to exist.
Like,
can we can we make this a unified image
listing image? Like.
What am I trying to say?
We have a separate image manager for
profile images and for listings.
Can we unify and have a single image
manager?
Yeah.
Do we want to do that is the next
question. Thank you, Abe.
Well, let's see, so...
I suppose.
If we have a single listing,
or not listing, an image process,
that just says, hey,
I want to upload a photo,
Service.
then I suppose the only difference
between the data,
what the back end knows what to do with
each individual photo upload is the
metadata on the photo, right?
So you upload it and say,
Metadata means this is a listing vertical
classifieds.
photo index zero, right?
And then it gets uploaded to the bucket,
M.
does all its checks,
fires off its pubsub message that it's
done.
And then the profile service would have
its back end process so that it goes, oh,
there was an image uploaded,
do I care about this one?
Is it a profile thing? No,
just back the message and move on.
That ignores it.
The listing service that would have its
piece,
it's listening to that same pub-sub topic.
So yeah,
already we do messages and profiles use
the same image back end somewhat.
Profile does async signed URLs,
whereas messages uploads directly,
but they both go through the same service,
same.
back-end processes.
Yeah.
Does video have to be excluded from this
as well? Like,
I know that we made video its own, but...
Videos are very different processing
things. So I just, yeah,
Okay, then I won't worry about it.
I don't see a point in combining them
because most of it wouldn't be shared.
Okay.
Unless you just called it like a media
uploader, right?
But...
That's what I was kind of moving towards
asking.
Yeah, media. Yeah,
you could do a media uploader,
but you do need a whole separate video
processor versus image processor.
Yeah.
OK, so...
Abe,
where is the profile stuff being
processed?
What service in Marketplace backend?
It is not in Marketplace back. So I mean,
we do have, yeah,
It's A microservice.
so we do have Marketplace back end
service for picking up the pub sub events
in the profile stuff,
but there's a whole separate,
because we created this image service
before we.
Okay.
So, the image service,
if it's on separate deployment.
Switch to Marketplace backend.
Went with the mono repo.
Yeah.
Image Images Services.
And there's an image download and image
upload.
And originally we figured, hey,
we can make this work for listings too.
And we decided that we didn't need to
specify exact sizing for images.
We just do t-shirt sizing and so that we
could adjust the sizing later on if
needed.
And we thought it would be great if we
just.
Resized when they're requested and cached,
and so we put a CDN in front of the image
download,
and so when different sizes are requested,
it just resizes it, stores it at the CDN,
and they get...
That's how they get her handled.
But anyway,
that's not what was implemented on
listings.
So it's a different concept altogether
that we were hoping we could move towards,
but it was never adopted probably because
it wasn't a drop-in replacement.
So then how does listings do it today
then when it comes to getting different
They have a completely different service.
renditions?
They don't go through this service.
The filters are made on upload.
So where with the messages, images,
they get resized only when they're
requested for.
Yeah.
That's not the case with listings.
Listings just do all the resizing up
front and store those.
You do all the sizes and we store all the
sizes.
Then what has been the...
Even if they never get used.
So then the desire that is wanted in the
future is that we just upload the main
photo.
That's the only one that we store in GCS,
I'm guessing. Yeah, GCS.
And then the CDN just handles the...
the caching of different renditions.
Yeah,
but you don't want to have an infinite
number of renditions. We figured that,
you know, small, medium, large,
extra large was good enough.
And then you can do any small tweaks on
the front end just with CSS.
The CSS, yeah.
But yeah.
Okay, so then what is...
Are we required to then at least
currently upload and save all of the
different renditions today?
No,
the backend creates the different
renditions.
That's what I meant,
like the back end currently,
and which back end is like Cappy back end?
I'm not sure where we they build a new
image service.
It, it's the...
I'm pretty sure that was part of what
Stephen did as just the replacement.
So KAPI and KSL API,
they are just wrappers that push it along
to the new image service,
but the new image service functions the
same as what was happening before
independently in KSL API and KAPI,
which is making all of those renditions
on upload.
Okay, so it essentially just moved code.
Yeah.
Okay,
so I like being happy to a new service
and then rewrote it and go.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
And I haven't really worked with it a ton,
so I can't tell you a whole lot about it.
Yeah,
I'm probably going to not try to add any.
Caching and like removing any of that
functionality during this thing is just
making it possible to upload.
Yeah.
But we do have the pattern already
established where messages is concerned,
so.
That pattern can be reused in that sense.
Yeah, it's just the.
I I don't think I want to worry about
trying to change that pattern for
listings during this.
I think it's something that we could
Yeah.
probably argue for later.
So that's just going to add up a lot of
extra scope.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure that's why it was done
that way in the 1st place.
Done, Dare.
Yeah.
Drop-in replacement, yeah.
Okay.
Alright, anything else?
Not for me.
OK, alright, if.
additional thoughts coming to you guys
over the next couple of days,
just send them my way.
Right, thanks for your time.
Yeah.